<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on octooAI</title>
    <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on octooAI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://octooai.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/semantic_seg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/semantic_seg/</guid>
      <description>We developed a real-time semantic segmentation models for identifying humans in video streams across web, Windows, and macOS. Designed a comprehensive library, abstracting complex tasks such as pre and post-processing and multithreading, allowing seamless client integration. This impactful project significantly enhanced the efficiency and ease of deploying advanced segmentation capabilities in diverse applications, without clients navigating the technical depths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image generation with Large Langugage Models</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/gen_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/gen_ai/</guid>
      <description>Developed a generative AI model capable of producing data from textual input, incorporating segmentation masks to eliminate the need for subsequent annotation. This innovation not only curtails costs but also ensures the generation of richer and more diverse training data for enhanced model performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic segmentation for autonomous vehicles</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/robo_cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/robo_cart/</guid>
      <description>We worked on an autonomous delivery robot project, focusing on real-time semantic segmentation for autonomous driving on edge devices. Our model adeptly handled a range of environmental challenges, including varying weather conditions and day-to-night transitions, ensuring robust and reliable robot navigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Networks (Research)</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/plugin_net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/plugin_net/</guid>
      <description>We introduced the Plugin Networks, an innovation enhancing model flexibility. These auxiliary networks, attached to original models, enable the alteration of model behavior without the necessity of retraining the foundational structure. While our focus was predominantly on discriminative models, the versatile application also extends to generative models, showcasing its broad utility. We used a simialr idea in our Image Generation project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food recognition for intelligent oven</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/oven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/oven/</guid>
      <description>We developed a food recognition model for intelligent ovens, I successfully designed a system capable of distinguishing among 100+ food classes. Prioritizing both compute and memory efficiency, the model was optimized for local deployment on edge devices, ensuring swift and accurate in-device food identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient monitoring -- action recognition</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/smarthome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/smarthome/</guid>
      <description>An action recognition system tailored for monitoring senior individuals in nursing homes. The model was adept at observing the well-being of residents, especially those with dementia and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, by proficiently detecting routine actions, such as breakfast preparation, ensuring consistent care and early anomaly detection</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People ReIdentification in crowded scenes</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/queue/</guid>
      <description>Contributed to a people re-identification project designed for theme parks, aiming to gauge the rate of queue progression. In the face of challenges like overlapping and occlusion in crowded scenarios, the system effectively distinguished individual identities. This methodology was subsequently patented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pose estimation and segmentation for neuro-therapy</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/therapy/</guid>
      <description>This project was aimed at enhancing recovery processes in neurotherapy. We developed a model for pose detection and segmentation, which played a crucial role in monitoring exercises and tracking patients&amp;rsquo; progress, ensuring more personalized and effective recovery pathways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parcel recognition system in warehouses</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/parcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/parcel/</guid>
      <description>A parcel detection and tracking system, tailored for efficient parcel management in expansive warehouses. The project entailed training robust models and crafting an efficient library to ensure real-time functionality within high-resolution camera networks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teleoperation for autonomus vehicles</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/tele_op/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/tele_op/</guid>
      <description>The development of a teleoperation library for autonomous vehicles, ensuring efficient data streaming and enhanced remote control. This advancement played a role the safety aspects of autonomous vehicle operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Segmentation from fMRI scans.</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/med_segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/med_segmentation/</guid>
      <description>The project focused on developing models for organ segmentation from fMRI and CT scans. The work required building models capable of efficiently operating on high-volume 3D data, ensuring precise and reliable segmentation outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectrometre calibration -- European Space Agency Project</title>
      <link>https://octooai.github.io/experience/esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://octooai.github.io/experience/esa/</guid>
      <description>We paricipated in the calibration of the SPIRE Fourier-Transform Spectrometer on the HERSCHEL space observatory, focusing on ensuring its accurate and reliable operation for space observations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
